American Society for Public Administration (ASPA), Capital District Chapter; Records apap009
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Subject Files, 1953; 1959-1960; 1963-1989; 3; 4 cubic ft.
  - Section for Women in Public Administration (SWPA), 1987 (Box 3 (3-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - "Smoking as a Condition of Employment: An Informational Brief". Prepared by: Elliott I. Alvarado, 1987 (Box 3 (3-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Society for the Advancement of Management, 1979 (Box 3 (3-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - State Academy for Public Administration, 1977 (Box 3 (3-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Treasurer's Report, 1984-1986 (Box 3 (3-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - "Women on the Move". An ASPA Conference, 1986 (Box 3 (3-Subject Files), Folder 10)
- Annual Institute, Records, 1965-1966; 1970; 1977-1979; 1983; 1985-1989; 4; 1 cubic ft.
  This series contains the records from the chapter's annual institutes. Types of records include minutes, correspondence, and planning documents. The annual institutes are small conferences centered around a subject in public administration. The institutes include sessions on more specific topics, installation of ASPA officers and the presentation of ASPA's annual awards. For the agenda to the annual institutes, see the publications file. ASPA--Empire State Capital Area Chapter.
  Arranged chronologically and alphabetically thereunder.
  - Annual Institute--Planning Documents, 1965 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 1)
  - Annual Institute--Planning Documents, 1966 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 2)
  - Annual Institute--Planning Documents, 1970 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 3)
  - Annual Institute--Planning Documents, 1977 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 4)
  - Annual Institute--Planning Documents, 1978 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 5)
  - Annual Institute--Planning Documents, 1979 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 6)
  - Annual Institute--Planning Documents, 1983; 4 folders (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 7-10)
  - Annual Institute--Advertising, 1986 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 11)
  - Annual Institute--Biographies of Speakers, 1986 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 12)
  - Annual Institute--Budget, 1986 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 13)
  - Annual Institute--General Correspondence, 1986 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 14)
  - Annual Institute--Meeting Schedules and Minutes, 1986 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 15)
  - Annual Institute--Panels and Sessions, 1986 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 16)
  - Annual Institute--Program and Committee Members, 1986 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 17)
  - Annual Institute--Site Arrangements, 1986 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 18)
  - Annual Institute--Women's Opportunities Conference, 1986 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 19)
  - Annual Institute--Administration, 1987 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 20)
  - Annual Institute--Attendance, 1987 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 21)
  - Annual Institute--Awards Ceremony, 1987 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 22)
  - Annual Institute--Awards Correspondence, 1987 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 23)
  - Annual Institute--Awards Luncheon, 1987 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 24)
  - Annual Institute--Bids for Management Services, 1987 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 25)
  - Annual Institute--Committee Meeting Agenda and Minutes, 1987 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 26)
  - Annual Institute--Council and SAPA, 1987 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 27)
  - Annual Institute--Exhibitors, 1987 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 28)
  - Annual Institute--Facilitators for Academic Papers, 1987 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 29)
  - Annual Institute--Financial Statements, 1987 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 30)
  - Annual Institute--Hospitality Reception, 1987 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 31)
  - Annual Institute--Leaflets, 1987 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 32)
  - Annual Institute--Meeting Agendas and Minutes, 1987 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 33)
  - Annual Institute--Photographs, Negatives and Contact Sheets, 1987 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 34)
  - Annual Institute--Photographs of Panelists, 1987 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 35)
  - Annual Institute--Planning Committee, 1987 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 36)
  - Annual Institute--Planning Committee, Membership Lists, 1987 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 37)
  - Annual Institute--Program Planning, 1987 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 38)
  - Annual Institute--Programs, 1987 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 39)
  - Annual Institute--Public Relations, 1987 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 40)
  - Annual Institute--Publicity, 1987 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 41)
  - Annual Institute-- Registrations and Budget, 1987 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 42)
  - Annual Institute--Schedules, 1987 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 43)
  - Annual Institute--Speakers, 1987 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 44)
  - Annual Institute--Vendors and Advertisements, 1987 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 45)
  - Annual Institute--Women's Conference, 1987 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 46)
  - Annual Institute--Awards, 1988 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 47)
  - Annual Institute--Bids for Management Services, 1988 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 48)
  - Annual Institute--Bids for Management Services, No Bids, 1988 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 49)
  - Annual Institute--Budget, 1988 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 50)
  - Annual Institute--Career Development Conference, 1988 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 51)
  - Annual Institute--Committee Members, 1988 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 52)
  - Annual Institute--Evaluations, 1988 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 53)
  - Annual Institute--Handouts, 1988 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 54)
  - Annual Institute--Letter to Edward V. Regan, 1988 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 55)
  - Annual Institute--Panels, 1988 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 56)
  - Annual Institute--Programs, 1988 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 57)
  - Annual Institute--Publicity, 1988 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 58)
  - Annual Institute--Registration, 1988 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 59)
  - Annual Institute--Schedules for Conference, 1988 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 60)
  - Annual Institute--Site Arrangements, 1988 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 61)
  - Annual Institute--Speakers, 1988 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 62)
  - Annual Institute--Exhibitor Listings, 1989 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 63)
  - Annual Institute--Planning, 1989 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 64)
  - Annual Institute--Programs, 1989 (Box 1 (4-Annual Institute, Records), Folder 65)
- Committee Files, 1961-1966; 1968-1971; 1975-1988; 5; 1.25 cubic ft.
  This series contains records of the committees of the Capital District chapter of ASPA. Many of the records are not the official committee records but rather the retained records of members of the committees. The one apparent exception is the records of the Long Range Planning Committee, which include minutes of committee meetings and which were divided by type into individual folders. Some of the committees are represented by only one folder, but other committees (apparently with more duties or members) have larger files--the Awards Committee, the Membership Committee, and the Training and Professional Development Committee.
  - Awards Committee, 1964-1965 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 1)
  - Awards Committee, 1969-1971 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 2)
  - Awards Committee, 1970-1971 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 3)
  - Awards Committee, 1971 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 4)
  - Awards Committee, 1975 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 5)
  - Awards Committee, 1976 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 6)
  - Awards Committee, 1977 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 7)
  - Awards Committee, 1978 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 8)
  - Awards Committee, 1979 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 9)
  - Awards Committee, 1984 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 10)
  - Awards Committee, 1984-1985 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 11)
  - Insurance Committee, 1968 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 12)
  - Long Range Planning Committee--Agenda & Minutes, 1986 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 13)
  - Long Range Planning Committee--Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 14)
  - Long Range Planning Committee--Public Administration Associates Program, 1986 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 15)
  - Luncheon Forum Committee, 1976; 1983 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 16)
  - Membership Committee, 1961 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 17)
  - Membership Committee, 1962-1963 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 18)
  - Membership Committee, 1964 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 19)
  - Membership Committee, 1965-1966 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 20)
  - Membership Committee, 1968 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 21)
  - Membership Committee, 1975-1976 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 22)
  - Membership Committee, 1976-1977 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 23)
  - Membership Committee, 1977-1978 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 24)
  - Membership Committee, 1978-1979 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 25)
  - Membership Committee, 1979-1980 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 26)
  - Membership Committee, 1980 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 27)
  - Nominating Committee, 1975 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 28)
  - Nominating Committee, 1976-1977 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 29)
  - Nominating Committee, 1977-1978 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 30)
  - Nominating Committee, 1979-1980; 1982 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 31)
  - Nominating Committee, 1988 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 32)
  - Policy Issues Committee, 1977-1978 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 33)
  - Program Committee, 1984-1985 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 34)
  - Public Policy Issues Committee--Reports, 1976 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 35)
  - Public Policy Issues Committee, 1982-1983 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 36)
  - Public Policy Issues Committee--Workforce Planning Statement, 1983-1984 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 37)
  - Public Policy Issues Committee, 1984; 2 folders (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 38-39)
  - Public Policy Issues Committee, 1984-1985 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 40)
  - Public Policy Issues Committee--Correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 41)
  - Strategic Planning Committee, 1982-1988 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 42)
  - Task Force on Public Policy Issues, 1980-1983 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 43)
  - Task Force on Training and Professional Development, 1984 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 44)
  - Training and Professional Development Committee, 1979-1980 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 45)
  - Training and Professional Development Committee, 1980-1981 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 46)
  - Awards Committee--S. Kenneth Howard Award, 1986 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 47)
  - Long Range Planning Committees, 1984-1986 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 48)
  - Long Range Planning Committee Memoranda, 1986-1988 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 49)
  - Long Range Planning Committee--Public Administration Associates (PAA), 1985-1986 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 50)
  - Nominating Committee, 1983-1984 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 51)
  - Program Committee, 1983 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 52)
  - Program Committee, 1984-1985 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 53)
  - Program Committee, 1985-1987 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 54)
  - Program Committee Correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 55)
  - Public Policy Issues Committee Correspondence, 1985-1987 (Box 1 (5-Committee Files), Folder 56)
- Secretary's Files, 1976-1977; 1980-1981; 6; 0.25 cubic ft.
  This series consists of the chapter secretary's day files. The years 1978 and 1979 are missing, but otherwise the day files give a chronological account of correspondence and other transactions from 1976 to 1981.
  - Day File, 1976-1977 (Box 1 (6-Secretary's Files), Folder 1)
  - Day File, 1977-1978 (Box 1 (6-Secretary's Files), Folder 2)
  - Day File, 1980 (Box 1 (6-Secretary's Files), Folder 3)
  - Day File, 1980-1981 (Box 1 (6-Secretary's Files), Folder 4)
- Publications, 1952; 1956-1983; 1985-1989; 7; 1 cubic ft.
  The publications series includes publications printed by either the Capital District Chapter of ASPA or the national association. The most important publications in this series are the agendas for the chapter's annual institutes, the chapter's annual reports, and the chapter's newsletters. A fairly large section of this series consists of handbooks the national association published as guides for the local chapters.
  - Annual Institute--Agenda, 1963-1966 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 1)
  - Annual Institute--Agenda, 1967-1971 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 2)
  - Annual Institute--Agenda, 1972-1978; 1980-1983; 1985 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 3)
  - Annual Meeting Programs, 1963; 1966-1970; 1972; 1974-1975; 1977-1979 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 4)
  - Annual Reports of Capital District Chapter of ASPA, 1956-1961 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 5)
  - Annual Reports of Captital District Chapter of ASPA, 1963-1968; 1974-1978; 1981; 1987 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 6)
  - ASPA News, Vol. 4, 1985-1986 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 7)
  - ASPA News, Vol. 5, 1986-1987 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 8)
  - ASPA News, Vol. 6, 1987-1988 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 9)
  - ASPA News, Vol. 7, 1988-1989 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 10)
  - Capital District Chapter, 1989 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 11)
  - Chapter Officers Newsletter, 1976-1981 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 12)
  - Handbook for Chapters, 1966 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 13)
  - Handbook for Chapters, 1967-1969 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 14)
  - Handbook for Chapters, 1969-1970 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 15)
  - Handbook for Chapters, 1975-1977 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 16)
  - Handbook for Chapters, 1978-1979 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 17)
  - How-To-Handbook, Undated (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 18)
  - Leaflets and Pamphlets, 1962-1968; 1971; ca. 1978; 1982; 1989 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 19)
  - Membership Directory, 1988-1989 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 20)
  - Meeting Announcements, 1967-1968; 1978-1981 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 21)
  - Newsletters of Capital District Chapter of ASPA, 1966-1968; 1975-1981 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 22)
  - Newsletters of Capital District Chapter of ASPA, 1982-1983 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 23)
  - Pamphlets from National ASPA, 1978-1979; 1989 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 24)
  - Programs for Anniversary Dinners of the Albany Graduate Program in Public Administration, 1952; 1957 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 25)
  - Public Service Frontiers, 1987-1988 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 26)
  - Reprint of a Series of Articles on the Constitutional Convention, 1967 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 27)
  - The Right Word: Guidelines for Avoiding Sex-Biases Language, ca. 1985 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 28)
  - Whole ASPA Catalog, 1985-1986 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 29)
  - Whole ASPA Catalog, 1986-1987 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 30)
- NY-SCAN Educational Programs, 1988; 8; 0.5 cubic ft.
  Contains videotapes of ASPA educational programs broadcast on NY-SCAN on topics such as labor shortages, ethics, AIDS, and waste management.
  - "A Coming Labor Shortage?", 7 May 1988 (Box 1 (8-NY-SCAN Educational Programs), Folder 1)
  - Welcome by Richardson, 17 May 1988 (Box 1 (8-NY-SCAN Educational Programs), Folder 2)
  - "The Ethics Triangle", 17 May 1988 (Box 1 (8-NY-SCAN Educational Programs), Folder 3)
  - "AIDS Policy", 17 May 1988 (Box 1 (8-NY-SCAN Educational Programs), Folder 4)
  - "Solid Waste Management", 18 May 1988 (Box 1 (8-NY-SCAN Educational Programs), Folder 5)
  - Luncheon, 18 May 1988 (Box 1 (8-NY-SCAN Educational Programs), Folder 6)
    ASPA--Empire State Capital Area Chapter.